# Jeronim Matijević

Zagreb, Croatia

🗷 jeronim96@gmail.com | 🛪 jere357.github.io | 🖸 github.com/jere357 | 🤗 huggingface.co/cropinky | 🗖 linkedin.com/in/jere357

### Personal Profile

Graduate student at the Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing, Zagreb enrolled in the Computer Science MSc programme. Passionate about neural networks for all purposes, with years of experience in training models for various tasks.

Fields of interest:

• Standard computer vision (classification, object detection, segmentation), generative models, neural radiance fields, depth estimation, image restoration and superresolution.

### **Education**

#### **Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing**

Zagreb, Croatia

MSc in Computer Science

Sept 2018 - Current

Courses worth mentioning: Analysis and text retrieval, Neural networks, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Statistical
Analysis of Data, Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures, Scripting languages, Computer Graphics

#### **Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing**

Zagreb, Croatia

**BSc in Computer Science** 

2015 - 2018

• Bsc Thesis: Method for counting people in sequences of images: youtube clip

#### Science and mathematics high school

Split, Croatia

High School

2011 - 2015

• Participated in physics, math and programming competitions at various levels

### Work Experience\_

**TensorPix** Zagreb, Croatia

Computer Vision Engineer/researcher

May 2023 - Current

• Working on image/video restoration and superresolution

#### **Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing**

Zagreb, Croatia

Researcher on the SOVA project

April 2022 - April 2023

- A collaboration between academia and industry. We helped develop solutions for inventory management in retail environments using computer vision. project website
- Studied the state of the art in depth estimation, neural radiance fields and oriented bounding box detection
- Used my novel evaluation metric to significantly reduce the memory footprint of my network.
- Defined my master's thesis which will focus on adding additional channel features to images with hopes of improving object detection networks as well as defining a "confusion matrix" for object detection evaluation

AI Technologies, d.o.o. Zagreb, Croatia

Computer Vision Engineer

April 2021 - September 2021

- Proof-of-concept project
- Goal of the project was detection of broken insulators on powerlines. Data was gathered from drones.
- The pipeline I constructed took the high quality videos from the NAS disk, downscaled their resolution/FPS and sent them into a insulator
  detection network. Then it extracted those insulators from the high quality video frames we started from. Those high-resolution insulator
  images were then sent to a classification network which decided if they were broken or not. All the broken insulators and the ordinal number
  of the transmission tower were stored in a csv file.
- · Closely coordinated with my colleagues who worked as annotators in order for us to have the best possible data

#### Skills

**Python** Pytorch (lightning), TF/jax XGBoost, openMMlab tensorboard, wandb, openCV, kornia, sklearn, numpy, shutil, multiprocessing

**Programming** Linux(7 years, on laptop + dual boot on PC), Docker, instant-ngp, ffmpeg, bash, C/C++, SQL/NoSQL

**Miscellaneous** Reading ML papers, Linux, ŁTĘX(Overleaf), CVAT, git, WeakAuras

AUGUST 8, 2023

## **University/Hobby Projects**

I have created my own website to go in depth on all the projects I've worked on over the years, there i go more in depth explaining what I did and how + I wanted less words in my CV.

#### My website/blog

#### A world of warcraft fishing bot using computer vision

Hobby

• Check out the github repository here: **repo link** 

#### **Projected GAN for art generation**

Hobby

• Check out the demo here: huggingface space

#### **Method for People Counting From Image Sequence**

Bachelor Thesis, mentor: Sven Lončarić

• Check out the short demo here: youtube video

#### Music genre classification from lyrics

Text Analysis and Retrieval course project

• You can check out the project report here: Project Report

#### Pix2pixGAN for generating facial expressions

Neural Network course project

• You can check out the **Project Report** (This one is in Croatian)

#### Fine-tuning english GPT-2 for rap lyric generation

Hobby

• Check out the demo here: huggingface space

#### Retinal fluid segmentation using 2D U-net

Graduate project

• This was done as my graduate project, the dataset I had was the same one used in the **Retouch Challenge**. Experimented with different/new loss functions and observed how the end result changes with respect to the loss function with interesting results

#### **Using ESRGAN for achieving superresolution**

Seminar Course

• Studied GANs and how they could be used for superresolution in images, and various difficulties the traditional approach had in achieving superresolution

#### Awards and honors

**Leader/Organizer of the sports climbing section at my university,** For two years I was responsible for

leading the sports climbing section for my university's PE course.

Croatian national high school physics competition 2014,

# Languages and hobbies

**English** Fluent **Croatian** Native

**Hobbies** Working with PC hardware, music, video games, bouldering, film,

August 8, 2023